<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ALL Lego Robot Game</title>
    <description>My IPP for the Lego Robot Project. Contains weekly updates of our progress with regards to our game. Powered by Jekyll and Github pages.
</description>
    <link>edprince.u/lego//</link>
    <atom:link href="edprince.u/lego//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 14:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 14:59:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Testing on the map</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have been working on the map itself, creating a modular maze that the robot
can solve. Using large tiles, and different colours of tape for the robot to
follow, we have begun testing to see if our robot can solve the maze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;theory-behind-the-maze-solving-robot&quot;&gt;Theory Behind the Maze Solving Robot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 4 colours used in the maze, green, red, black and blue. Each holds
distinct significance. The robot starts on a green square, and moves along the
black lines. Every single intersection has a blue square. When the robot hits
the blue square, it will always turn left, whenever it meets brown, it will do a
180 degree turn, and carry on. This works providing the maze can be abstracted
to a tree, rather than a graph. If cycles are formed in the maze, then the robot
could enter and infinite loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;difficulties-this-week&quot;&gt;Difficulties this week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problems are arising, not through failed concept, but rather though physical
difficulties with the maze. For example a shadow being cast by overlapping
cardboard is registering as black through the optical sensor, and is therefore
causing the robot to follow it. Sometimes the turn happens at the wrong angle
and the robot becomes unaligned. My preference for solving this is to create a
more intelligent line following program, rather than the current code, with
simply makes the robot turn right when it sees brown. This works fine as long as
the robot is moving, slightly angled to the left, meaning when a turn does not
result at a good angle, the robot can come off the maze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;objects-obstacles&quot;&gt;Objects, obstacles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have created cardboard objects and obstacles. The robot will need to pick up
and reposition obstacles next to the track, and pick up and place objects in the
container at the end of the maze. Some obstacles may have time limits on them,
and if the robot cannot reposition them correctly when the timer runs out, the
game is over.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 18:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/11/15/week8.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/11/15/week8.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bluetooth and gameplay</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;bluetooth&quot;&gt;Bluetooth&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite getting the bluetooth working with one app earlier on in the process,
we needed to use bluetooth and a certain app to interact with the robot
successfully. The new app allows us to send/recieve messages to and from the
robot, and should not at all interfere with the existing program on the robot
itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gameplay&quot;&gt;Gameplay&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also changed the gameplay slightly. After conversing with the tutors, we
realised that we needed to add more complexity. Since the line following was
presenting many difficulties (due to the placement of the sensor, and the tracks
on the robot), we decided to focus more heavily on an adaptable-maze-solving
robot. The maze shall be built using large square tiles with different tape
pathways. The tile approach allows us to change/adapt the maze and prove that
our robot can still solve it. To make the game more interactable with users, we
have decided to place different types of object in the maze, and make the user
decide which objects to pick up/where to put them. This can be done with the
bluetooth messaging.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 15:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/11/09/week7.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/11/09/week7.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 4 roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;flowchart-exmaple&quot;&gt;Flowchart exmaple&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/iiAEHx5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Flowchart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;update-to-movement&quot;&gt;Update to movement&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movement testing
Object pickup testing
Line following testing
Game update&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 18:16:53 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/10/16/week4.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/10/16/week4.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 3 roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;movement&quot;&gt;Movement&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we have added looped movement to the robot, so it will
continuously move, and (mostly) doesn’t crash into any walls. Exceptions
have proven to be irregular objects like legs/chairs etc. It proves very
successful with regular walls though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week we have also successfully implemented mobile phone controlled
movement for the robot. This would allow the user to connect their phone
to the robot via bluetooth, and control the motors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;update-to-movement&quot;&gt;Update to movement&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to complexity and possible conflicts between the loaded program and
phone instructions, we have decided to attempt to automate the maze.
This will include implementing line following. We will also automate the
acquisition and transportation of the objects.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 18:16:53 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/10/16/week3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/10/16/week3.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 2 roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-robot&quot;&gt;The robot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we have finished building the robot, and added a touch and
optical sensor. We have also tested the optical and infra-red sensors
stopping the robot from crashing into walls. The optical sensor has
allowed us to react to detection of any of a selection of colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also experimented with playing sounds, both from the EV3 library
and our own custom mp3 tracks. Along with this, we succeeded in
displaying data on the display screen located on the brick of the robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also decided on our game as a maze, in which the robot has to
navigate, and react with various objects. This approach allows us to
have a reasonable amount of modularity for new obstacles in the maze.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 18:16:53 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/10/08/week2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/10/08/week2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 1 roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, we have now had two sessions on the project. We have decided on a game, a varied maze for the robot to
complete in as little time as possible, with obstacles it must tackle. We have set up a Google Docs for us
all to collaborate on, and a Facebook group to keep in communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-strengths&quot;&gt;My Strengths&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest strength in the field is web development, which in this project is likely not to be needed, at least
not much. After this, I feel I work well as part of a team, but would like to improve upon my ability to push
ideas forward, and not shy away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;our-game&quot;&gt;Our Game&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maze game should allow us to incorporate as many or as few of the robots potential capabilities as we can, 
as we can simply add in new obstacles that will challenge it. We need to work on the controlling of the robot. 
Ideally, we would have a player control it from either the computer or even better a smartphone, but this may
end up being impractically difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have talked about using the colour detection to detect an object and place it into the correct pot.
We wondered about there being physical obstacles for the robot to pick up in order to clear its path.
The display screen on the robot would allow us to display the number of points, most likely starting at x, 
and decrement by 1 per second, to leave the player with a final score at the end of the maze. The points may
stop decrementing when it passes a finish line of a certain colour, causing it to stop (and dance?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Movement will be essential to navigate through the maze.
The line following feature may be able to be added. We could start 3 pieces of string in the same place, and the 
robot would try and follow, making it random for the player which path the robot took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves:&lt;br /&gt;
 - Sound detection&lt;br /&gt;
 - Button press input&lt;br /&gt;
 - Line following&lt;br /&gt;
 - Responding to an event&lt;br /&gt;
 - Learning&lt;br /&gt;
 - Timing control for an activity (robot is sad if maze is not completed within a certain time limit?)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 18:16:53 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/10/01/week1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">edprince.u/lego//jekyll/update/2015/10/01/week1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
